bizarremag.com 2015-12-27

# Privacy Notice | Dennis Publishing

Last Updated January 2014

We have published a new cookie policy. It explains what cookies are and how we use them on our site. To learn more about cookies and their benefits, please view our cookie policy. If you'd like to disable cookies on this device, please visit [www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/) for more information on how to do this. Please be aware that parts of the site will not function correctly if you disable cookies. By using our websites you consent to our use of cookies on this device in accordance with our cookie policy unless you have disabled them.

### Dennis Publishing Privacy Notice

Your personal information is being processed by Dennis Publishing (UK) Ltd (“we”). We are committed to managing your personal information in accordance with current legislation and best practice. Our aim is to be responsible, relevant and secure when using your data. You can find out more about us by visiting [www.dennis.co.uk/about-us](http://www.dennis.co.uk/about-us).

Whenever you provide personal information we will treat that information in accordance with this Notice. We endeavour at all times to keep your data accurate and secure, and to honour your data preferences with regard to receipt of direct marketing e.g. email, mobile messaging and mobile telephone calls. 

Dennis Publishing (UK) Ltd publishes over fifty magazines, websites, e-zines and mobile phone sites (brands) all of which are governed by this Privacy Notice. For an up to date list of these brands please visit [www.dennis.co.uk/brands](http://www.dennis.co.uk/brands/). Below is a non-exhaustive list of our well-known brands.

Auto Express, bit-tech, Bizarre, Channel Pro, Computer Shopper, Custom PC, Digital SLR Photography, EVO, Fortean Times, iMotor, IT Pro, Know Your Mobile, MacUser, Men's Fitness, Micro Mart, Monkey, Octane, PC Pro, The Week and Viz.

Dennis Publishing (UK) Ltd includes subsidiary companies Dennis Publishing Ltd, Evo Publications Ltd, The Week Ltd, Dennis Lifestyle Ltd, It’s in the Bag Ltd, Three PM Ltd, Four PM Ltd, First Post Newsgroup Ltd, Halo Publishing Ltd, Bit Publishing Ltd, Octane Media Ltd and Octane (Media) Holdings Ltd. Choice Publishers Limited, The Magazine Group, Dennis Interactive Ltd, I Feel good (Holdings) limited and I Feel Good Limited.

Dennis Publishing (UK) Ltd had formed partnerships with a variety of carefully selected companies. Below is a non-exhaustive list of our key partners:  
IPC Media Ltd  
Jellyfish Online Marketing  
Audience Science  
Hearst UK trading as The National Magazine Company  
Hearst UK trading as Hachette Filipacchi  

## What information we collect

To provide you with the best possible customer experience we may ask you to submit personal information such as your name, postcode, email address and mobile phone number. Providing this personal information helps us to provide you with a better experience e.g. not having to login to websites each time you visit and showing you content that really interests you.  
Additionally we use web technologies e.g. cookies and web beacons, to automatically track and log limited personal data and link this with information you or other suppliers have provided. For detailed information on Cookies and how you can choose to allow or prevent sites accessing cookies, see [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).  
Anonymous data will be recorded for the purpose of reporting web traffic statistics, advertisement 'click-throughs', and/or other activities on our sites.

Dennis Publishing may sometimes use cookie technology to help improve its digital marketing campaigns and improve user experience across its products. This technology allows Dennis Publishing to target relevant adverts to you across a number of other websites that share the same advertising technology platforms. Third party vendors including partners like Google serve advertising across the Internet based on cookies which are left on your device when you visit a website. These cookies help target relevant advertising to our users based on previous visits and behaviour. You can opt out of Google’s use of cookies by visiting [Google’s Ads Settings](http://www.google.com/settings/ads) or you can opt out of additional third-party vendor cookies by visiting the [Network Advertising Initiative opt out page](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/).

Furthermore we work with our partners Audience Science, to carry out Online Behavioural Advertising on our websites. Online Behavioural Advertising aims to provide you with more carefully targeted advertising. If you wish to know more about Online Behavioural Advertising or you wish to opt out of Online Behavioural Advertising by Audience Science please go to  [ www.youronlinechoices.com/uk  ](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk) .

Our iPad, Android and other ‘apps’ may use a service called Flurry Analytics to collect user data which we use to learn about our readers and improve the app. To find out more, visit <http://www.flurry.com/about-us/legal/privacy.html>. You can opt out at any time by visiting <http://www.flurry.com/resources/privacy.html>.

**How we use your data**

The personal information we obtain will be used for the following purposes.

Technical administration of the web site, enhancing your experience of the site, research and development, customer service, marketing, advertising targeting and making your personal data available to selected partners. This will include Dennis and our partners sending you information about products and services that will be relevant to you, by email, mobile messaging, postal mail or direct telephone contact. All of the above are subject to your stated preferences; we and our content partners will always make it clear how you can prevent i.e. opt-out of these uses.

We may use third party suppliers to provide part of our service to you. In some circumstances these providers may be based in countries outside the European Economic Area whose laws provide for a different standard of protection for your personal information than that provided under UK Law. In such circumstances we will have in place strict contractual arrangements that will require your information is processed securely, at least to a standard equivalent to the UK Data Protection Act 1998.  
Your personal data will not be disclosed to state institutions and authorities except if required by law or other regulation. Before we release data on this basis, we will ensure that the information is being provided to a genuine and properly authorised investigation. If we are not satisfied that there are valid grounds for releasing the information, the Data Protection Act does not oblige us to do so. If we refuse to release the information, law enforcement agencies may obtain a court order requiring us to provide it. ****

**Individual Choice** ****

You can change your personal information preferences and/or details at any time. As a magazine subscriber you can access your preferences by logging on to www.subsinfo.co.uk using your SubsInfo password. If you have registered on a Dennis Publishing (UK) Ltd website you can access your personal information preferences by logging in to our registration system and using the username and password details you selected. You can also unsubscribe to any/all lists by sending an email request to [privacy@dennis.co.uk](mailto:privacy@dennis.co.uk). (including your full name, postcode and magazine subscription / website registration / competition information). 

You will ALWAYS be given a straightforward way to opt out from our direct marketing each time you receive a communication from us or one of our advertising partners.

**Access to Personal Information** **  
** If you wish, you can obtain a copy of any personal information we have about you by sending your request to The Data Controller, Dennis Publishing (UK) Ltd, 30 Cleveland Street, London, W1T 4JD.  
We will provide you, at no charge, with a hard copy of the personal data that we keep about you within 30 days, although we will require proof of your identity. If you consider that the information we hold about you is incorrect, you may where appropriate, have the data erased, amended or updated. 

**Personal information security**

Dennis Publishing (UK) Ltd security policies, rules and technical measures have been implemented to protect your personal information from unauthorised or improper use and from accidental loss.

All our employees and data processors that have access to, and are associated with, the processing of your personal information are legally obliged to respect the confidentiality of your data and are bound by contract to do so.

Note that some of our websites provide forums where you can post information. When you do so, be aware that other visitors may collect any information you make public.

**Privacy Support**

If you have an enquiry or concern about our Privacy Notice, please contact: The Data Controller, Dennis Publishing (UK) Ltd, 30 Cleveland Street, London, W1T 4JD. If you are not satisfied with our response you may wish to contact the Information Commissioner via their [website](http://www.ico.gov.uk/)

If we decide to change our Privacy Notice we will post these changes on this page so that you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it and in what circumstances we disclose it.  
In the event of any part of Dennis Publishing (UK) Ltd either being sold or going into receivership, we reserve the right to continue to share your data to third parties in accordance with the latest preferences you have provided. You will be informed should any change of ownership occur, and the new owner will manage your personal information preferences.
